<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Itarow</title>
    <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Itarow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Itarow</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 19:48:07 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.itarow.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DG&#39;hAck 2023 - L&#39;an 1, et puis l&#39;an 2 - Shinji &amp; Itarow</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/l_an_1_et_puis_l_an_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 19:48:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/l_an_1_et_puis_l_an_2/</guid>
      <description>Solution du challenge &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;an 1, et puis l&amp;rsquo;an 2&amp;rdquo; créé pour le DG&amp;rsquo;hAck 2023.
Description Sur le réseau de l&amp;rsquo;entreprise d&amp;rsquo;un ami, un employé a lancé un fichier inconnu provenant d&amp;rsquo;une clé USB. Apeuré, il s&amp;rsquo;est rendu à la DSI qui a réalisé un dump mémoire de la machine par précaution. Selon-eux il n&amp;rsquo;y a rien à craindre, la machine n&amp;rsquo;est pas compromise.
Mais quelques temps après avoir rebranché son PC sur le réseau, l&amp;rsquo;employé s&amp;rsquo;est mis à perdre certains de ses fichiers, pris de panique il a éteint sa machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbhack 2023 - pacapable - Pwn</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/pacapable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 21:55:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/pacapable/</guid>
      <description>Here is the solution of the Pwn challenge &amp;ldquo;pacapable&amp;rdquo; which I create for barbhack CTF. The challenge was solved by only two teams.
Description Try to pwn this, I use qemu and another surprise as well, you have no chance :)
Solution Here is the docker file of the challenge :
FROM ubuntu:22.04 RUN apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp;\ apt install -y socat netcat qemu-user gcc-aarch64-linux-gnu gdb-multiarch RUN apt-get update RUN useradd --home-dir /home/pacapable --create-home pacapable RUN mkdir /home/pacapable/chall COPY .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbhack 2023 - RIP My PXE - Forensic</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/rip_my_pxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 20:58:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/rip_my_pxe/</guid>
      <description>Here is the solution of the challenge &amp;ldquo;RIP My PXE&amp;rdquo; which I create for barbhack CTF, the challenge is divided in three parts.
Step 1 Unfortunately! Our company&amp;rsquo;s PXE server and our super autoinstall were compromised and our new employees installed their PCs afterwards &amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s the dump of one of the machines we think has been compromised, please help us understand what the attacker has done. A first backdoor has been inserted so that the attacker can retrieve a shell, please find the domain, the port of the attacker&amp;rsquo;s C2, as well as the binary that triggers the backdoor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FCSC 2023 - Baleine sous graviers - Forensics</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/baleine_sous_graviers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 21:34:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/baleine_sous_graviers/</guid>
      <description>Here is the write-up of &amp;ldquo;Baleine sous graviers&amp;rdquo;, a forensics challenge of the FCSC 2023 which involves investigation of multiple pcap files.
Description The security analysts of a telecom operator are facing a major problem. For the past few days, an alert on their intrusion detection system keeps getting raised by their behavioral analysis probe. The probe indicates that the traffic captured on some core network links is abnormal. Here is the topology of the operator&amp;rsquo;s core network: After several nights of traffic analysis, our analysts were unable to find the cause of this alert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FCSC 2023 - Ransomémoire - Forensics</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/ransomemoire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 21:34:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/ransomemoire/</guid>
      <description>Here is the write-up of &amp;ldquo;Ransomémoire&amp;rdquo; series of forensic challenges of the FCSC 2023 which involves investigation of a Windows 10 memory dump. The series is divided in four parts.
Ransomémoire 0/4 - Pour commencer | Description You prepare to analyze a memory capture and note some information about the machine before diving into the analysis: username, machine name, browser used. The flag is in FCSC{&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;machine name&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;browser name&amp;gt;} format where: &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; is the name of the user using the machine, &amp;lt;machine name&amp;gt; is the name of the machine being analyzed, and &amp;lt;browser name&amp;gt; is the name of the running browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DG&#39;hAck 2022 - Sandchat</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/sandchat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 18:01:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/sandchat/</guid>
      <description>Here is the write up of the Sandchat challenge of the DG&amp;rsquo;hAck 2022 CTF. This challenge was in the system category but It more mix reverse and pwn skills, was fun to solve !
Vous disposez d&amp;rsquo;un acces ssh à une application de surveillance d&amp;rsquo;un serveur. Saurez vous en échapper ? Selon nos sources un service serait vulnérable sur cette machine. A vous de découvrir son point faible..
Part 1 - Sandbox shell escape To start the challenge we have an ssh access to a service which is sandboxed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RootMe CTF 2022 - Pwnanalyzed</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/pwnanalyzed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:38:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/pwnanalyzed/</guid>
      <description>This suite of challenges was created by voydstack for the RootMe CTF 2022.
For this suite of challenges, we have to analyze network capture realized during an exploit of an attacker. The goal is to find the flag exfiltrated by the attacker. These types of exploit could be related to Attack/Defense CTF where players exfiltrate flags with payload obfuscation to hide and to prevent defenders to replay or reverse their exploits easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HeroCTFv4 - Where_all_problems_starts</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/heroctfv4-where_all_problems_starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:15:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/heroctfv4-where_all_problems_starts/</guid>
      <description>HeroCTFv4 - Forensic - Where all problems start This is the write-up of &amp;ldquo;Where all problems start&amp;rdquo;, a forensic challenge of the HeroCTFv4 created by Worty . It is divided in four parts with four different files.
Part 1 - USB parition For a change of pace, a company has been attacked again... Nevertheless , the means used here is quite original, indeed, it would be apparently a food delivery man who would be at the origin of the initial compromise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FCSC2022 - R2D2</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/fcsc2022-r2d2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 22:47:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/fcsc2022-r2d2/</guid>
      <description>FCSC2022 - R2D2 Write-up Énoncé Le PDG de GoodCorp n&amp;rsquo;en démord pas : son téléphone est backdooré, et en plus de voler ses photos, on lui vole ses mots de passe, son historique de navigation, ses messages, etc. !
On vous confie l&amp;rsquo;analyse de son téléphone.
Consciencieux, vous décidez d&amp;rsquo;émuler complètement le téléphone, afin de pouvoir investiguer plus en profondeur.
fichiers : android.zip Comment lancer l&amp;rsquo;émulateur.pdf
Note : L&amp;rsquo;application Authenticator ne fait pas partie de l&amp;rsquo;épreuve</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FCSC2022 - MC Players</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/fcsc2022-mc_players/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 22:07:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/fcsc2022-mc_players/</guid>
      <description>FCSC 2022 - MC Players - Write-up Énoncé Cela fait plusieurs mois que le service de Dinnerbone permettant de récupérer
le statut d&amp;rsquo;un serveur Minecraft n&amp;rsquo;est plus actif. Nous avons donc décidé de proposer une alternative réutilisant sa librairie mcstatus.
https://mc-players.france-cybersecurity-challenge.fr/
Résolution Ici on se retrouve face à une appli web en white-box, c’est-à-dire que nous avons le code source de l’application à notre disposition. Cette application est développée en python avec le framework flask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BZHCTF 2022 - Des Deux Cotes 1/2</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/bzhctf_des-deux-cotes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 23:52:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/bzhctf_des-deux-cotes-1/</guid>
      <description>Voici le write-up du challenge &amp;ldquo;Des Deux Côtés 1/2&amp;rdquo; en catégorie Forensic que j&amp;rsquo;ai pu first blood lors du Breizh CTF.
Énoncé Voir les deux côtés de quelque chose, c&amp;rsquo;est toujours bon non ?
Vous êtes une APT et un de vos collègues a volé une machine chez une entreprise du CAC40, malheureusement, celle-ci ne veut plus démarrer.. Votre collègue étant un hacker en herbe, il a pensé à faire un dump mémoire avant que la machine rende l&amp;rsquo;âme !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BZHCTF 2022 - Le Stagiaire</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/bzhctf_le_stagiaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 12:07:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/bzhctf_le_stagiaire/</guid>
      <description>Voici le write-up du challenge &amp;ldquo;Le Stagiaire&amp;rdquo; en catégorie Forensic que j&amp;rsquo;ai pu first blood lors du Breizh CTF. Merci à l&amp;rsquo;organisation et l&amp;rsquo;ESN&amp;rsquo;HACK pour ce CTF fort sympathique ;)
Énoncé Un des stagiaires de votre entreprise a eu pour but pendant son stage de créer un document permettant de référencer les différents patchs à appliquer à une version de wordpress (core) pour améliorer la sécurité.
Tout son stage s&amp;rsquo;est déroulé tranquillement, le jour avant de partir, il a créé un github permettant d&amp;rsquo;appliquer toutes ses recommandations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoami</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 19:40:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/whoami/</guid>
      <description>Whoami Hi everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m Itarow, french student and passionate of cybersecurity. Here you will find some stuff related to infosec. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in Offensive content (especially binary exploitation) and Forensics.
Hope you will enjoy my posts :)
If you want to contact me, send me a message on Twitter or on Discord (0xItarow).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackthebox - Ophiuchi - Write up</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/hackthebox-ophiuchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 16:22:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/hackthebox-ophiuchi/</guid>
      <description>I rooted Ophiuchi which was a medium Linux machine. It implicates a flaw with YAML which allow to RCE. Apache tomcat credentials free, and a sudo capability to run a go file.
Foothold classic nmap :
➜ Ophiuchi nmap -A -p- -T4 10.10.10.227 PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.2p1 Ubuntu 4ubuntu0.1 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 8080/tcp open http Apache Tomcat 9.0.38 |_http-open-proxy: Proxy might be redirecting requests |_http-title: Parse YAML Service Info: OS: Linux; CPE: cpe:/o:linux:linux_kernel ```So we are going to see the HTTP port.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HeroCTFv3 - Box_dev0ps - Write up</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/heroctfv3-box_dev0ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 15:43:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/heroctfv3-box_dev0ps/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone, this is my write-up of the Box challenge from the HeroCTFv3, challenge which was created by xanhacks (https://twitter.com/xanhacks). The box was in three parts, first, get a shell on the first docker, after, get a shell on the second docker, and last part, get root privilege.
Foothold Nmap scan first (which was given) :
$ nmap -p 3000,8080,2222 box.heroctf.fr -sV Starting Nmap 7.91 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2021-04-18 22:30 CEST Nmap scan report for box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHACK CTF 2021 - RAID Dead Redemption - Write Up</title>
      <link>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/phack-ctf-2021_raid-dead-redemption_write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 15:30:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.itarow.xyz/posts/phack-ctf-2021_raid-dead-redemption_write-up/</guid>
      <description>This is the write-up of &amp;ldquo;RAID Dead Redemption&amp;rdquo; challenge. This was my favorite challenge of the PHACK CTF.
You work at the special brigade of the cyber defense service of the police station of Montargis. The hard drives of a woman have been seized and have just been transmitted to you. She is suspected of having downloaded numerous PNG and JPG files of which she did not have the intellectual property.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
